<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://landoty.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://landoty.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-04-26T23:12:19+00:00</updated><id>https://landoty.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Landen Doty</title><entry><title type="html">What I’m Reading (and why)</title><link href="https://landoty.github.io/blog/2023/what-im-reading/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I’m Reading (and why)" /><published>2023-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://landoty.github.io/blog/2023/what-im-reading</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://landoty.github.io/blog/2023/what-im-reading/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="a-gentleman-in-moscow---amor-towles">A Gentleman in Moscow - Amor Towles</h3>

<p><img style="float:left; max-width: 20%; max-height: 30%; display:flex;" class="pr-3" src="/assets/img/blog/gentleman_in_moscow.jpeg" /></p>

<p>I came across <em>A Gentleman in Moscow</em> through a Bill Gates review in 2019 and it has been sitting in my Amazon wish-list since. I stumbled upon it again when looking for a new book to take with me for spring break and it felt like the right time.</p>

<p><em>A Gentleman in Moscow</em> follows Count Alexander Ilyich Rostov, who, being deemed a threat and aristocrat by the Bolshevik’s in 1922, is sentenced to a lifelong house arrest in Moscow’s Metropol Hotel. Thusfar, the Count, as he is often referred to in the novel, is presented as a Rennaissance man of the time. Cuisine, music, literature, you name it. Whatever it may be, the Count is far from shy about sharing an anecdote before providing his opinion on the matter. However, with his almost uncanny charm and elegeance, the Count forces the reader to appreciate, almost admire, his every word.</p>

<p>I’m about 100 pages or so through the book and, while my progress has stagnated considerably (thanks, junior year CS), it’s definitely a tough one to put down. Add the fact that <em>A Gentlemen in Moscow</em> follows the same time period and events as one of my all-time favorites, <em>Animal Farm</em> by George Orwell, I’m eager to find some time to pick it back up.
<br clear="left" /></p>

<h3 id="a-higher-loyalty---james-comey">A Higher Loyalty - James Comey</h3>

<p><img style="float:left; max-width: 20%; max-height: 30%;" class="pr-3" src="/assets/img/blog/higher_loyalty.jpeg" /></p>

<p>Despite the mixed, largely divisive reviews, I was excited to get a copy of <em>A Higher Loyalty</em> by former FBI Director James Comey. Regardless of political affiliation, I see an opportunity to learn about leadership at the highest levels and how, even in career-threatening moments, how to maintain loyalty to the values we believe to be true. Admittedly, I am hopeful that this book doesn’t diverge too distantly into politcally-partisan discussions; however, I am intrigued about gaining some insight into the happenings of the recent administration.</p>

<p>I haven’t read past the Author’s Note at this point, so hang tight for further thoughts!
<br clear="left" /></p>

<h3 id="the-shellcoders-handbook-2nd-edition---anley-heasman-linder-and-richarte">The Shellcoder’s Handbook, 2nd Edition - Anley, Heasman, Linder, and Richarte</h3>

<p><img style="float:left; max-width: 20%; max-height: 30%;" class="pr-3" src="/assets/img/blog/shellcoders.jpeg" /></p>

<p>I bought this book through some extra scholarship funds I needed to use. I’ve been working (slowly) through some RE and exploit development materials, but felt that I needed a book to guide me moving forward. I’ll probably remove this from any future reading list since it’ll be more of a continuous learning material, but I thought it’d be good to share what I’m reading on the technical side.</p>

<p>I’m looking forward to really diving into the Windows sections along with the entire third part of the book, <em>Vulnerability Discovery</em>. Stay tuned and keep an eye on the projects section ;)
<br clear="left" /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="books" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[keeping track of what I'm reading, why I chose these books, and what I look to gain from them]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pwn.College Reverse Engineering</title><link href="https://landoty.github.io/blog/2023/pwnCollege-revEng/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pwn.College Reverse Engineering" /><published>2023-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://landoty.github.io/blog/2023/pwnCollege-revEng</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://landoty.github.io/blog/2023/pwnCollege-revEng/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="challenge-10">Challenge 1.0</h3>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>The challenge compares a user-input “license key” with the expected value.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The output of the program gives us insight into how our input is formatted and compared against the expected value</p>

    <p><img src="/assets/img/blog/pwn-rev1-1.png" class="img-fluid" /></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>As we can see, the first 5 ASCII characters are consumed, converted to hex, and compared against the expected value</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>We can simply convert the expected hex values to ASCII and supply as input to the challenge</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<details><summary><b>Solution</b></summary>
<p>

```bash
    $ python -c "print(chr(0x75)+chr(0x6d)+chr(0x6e)+chr(0x75)+chr(0x64))" | /challenge/babyrev_level1.0
```
</p>
</details>

<h3 id="challenge-11">Challenge 1.1</h3>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>This challenge is still comparing an user-input “license key” against the expected value.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>However, we are no longer provided any information about how our key is processed and what the expected value is…time to reverse!</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Debugging Symbols</strong> =&gt; None :/</p>

    <p><img src="/assets/img/blog/pwn-rev1-2.png" class="img-fluid" /></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Strings</strong> =&gt; ;)</p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>Using the <em>strings</em> command and grep’ing for a 5-length string, we get something promising…</p>

        <p><img src="/assets/img/blog/pwn-rev1-3.png" class="img-fluid" /></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Let’s modify this command to just pipe to the challenge binary:</p>

        <details><summary><b>Solution</b></summary>
  <p>
        
  ```bash
      $ strings /challenge/babyrev_level1.1 | egrep -E "^z.{4}" | /challenge/babyrev_level1.1
  ```
  </p>
  </details>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>BONUS: .data</strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>We can also dump the data section to read the license key (just as <em>strings</em> does)</p>

        <p><img src="/assets/img/blog/pwn-rev1-4.png" class="img-fluid" /></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="ctf" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[uploading some previous solutions from Pwn.College]]></summary></entry></feed>